米奇爾 你醒了嗎
Oh, Mitchell. Are you awake?
醒了 樓上的女士好像叫了一聲
Yeah, I think the lady upstairs just screamed.
-我們該去看看她嗎 -不 是我叫的
- Should we check on her? - No, that was me.
我剛剛淋浴時發生了很可怕的事
Something terrible just happened in the shower.
天啊 你又亂刮什么地方的毛了
Oh, God. What did you try to shave?
不 是我忘了
No, I forgot
《謝天謝地我是鄉下男孩》的歌詞
the words to "Thank God I'm A Country Boy."
好吧 兩分鐘前 我還在夢中
Okay, two minutes ago, I was on the back
和007丹尼爾·克雷格騎雪上摩托
of a snowmobile with Daniel Craig.
米奇爾 我整個童年都在唱那首歌
Mitchell, I sang that song my entire childhood.
假如我忘記了歌詞
If I can't remember the lyrics,
說明我完全忘記了自己的根
that means I've lost complete touch with my roots.
我怎么會讓這種事發生
How could I let this happen?
別對自己這么嚴苛
Don't be so hard on yourself.
我沒有 這大部分都要怪你
I'm not. This is mostly your doing.
我該猜到你會這么說
Should have seen that coming.
你用羞辱趕走了我心中的鄉下男孩
You have shamed the country boy out of me.
我一說"大伙兒"和"可勁兒"你就翻白眼
You roll your eyes when I say "y'all" or "fixin'".
還逼我把曬衣繩丟了
You made me take down our clothesline.
我只是叫你掛到后院去
I just asked that we put it in the backyard.
你知道我必須怎樣做
You know what I have to do.
-重新記歌詞 -養只雞
- Relearn the lyrics to -- - Get a chicken.
顯然 沒有法律條文規定
So, apparently, there's no legal reason
我們不能在后院養雞
why we can't have a chicken in our backyard,
我很徹底地查過資料
and-and I did a real deep dive.
這是廚房 我們最近重裝修過
Okay, so this is the kitchen, which we recently remodeled.
習慣他這副臭臉
Get used to that.
這是客廳
Okay, this is the living room.
好了 到時你和媽坐在椅子上
Okay, so, you and Mom will be in the chairs.
我 海莉和盧克坐在沙發上
Me, Haley, and Luke will be on the couch.
面試官就坐在這
And the interviewer will be right here.
艾麗克斯正在申請一份享有聲望的政府工作
Alex is up for a very prestigious government job
需要進行家庭面試
that requires a family interview.
以防他們帶了那種記憶消除器
In case they bring one of those memory zappers,
我把所有相關信息都寫在胳膊上了
I've Sharpied all the pertinent information on my arm --
個人識別碼之類的
PIN numbers, et cetera.
親愛的 你不是真心覺得他們會
Oh, honey, you don't think that they're really going to --
別擔心 妹子 我把你也寫上了
Oh, do not worry, little lady. I got you covered.
假如你真的想給面試官留個好印象
If you really want to impress the interviewer,
不如不經意地把這張我在健身房撿到的
why don't you try casually leaving out this completed
填滿的《紐約時報》填字謎放在桌上
New York Times crossword that I found at the gym?
參加槍戰只帶把刀怎么行
Why bring a knife to a gun fight?
不如我把傳家寶擺出來吧
How about I lay out the family heirloom?
1931年 曾祖父泰德·鄧菲
1931. Great-grandpa Ted Dunphy
在一個霧蒙蒙的夜晚從莫德斯托驅車南下
is driving south from Modesto one foggy evening.
他讓一個拋錨的摩托司機搭了便車
He picks up a stranded motorist
把他送到一間加油站
and drives him to a gas station.
那個人沒錢 所以泰德幫他付了油錢
The man has no money, so Ted pays for his gas.
那個人在餐巾紙上畫了張速寫感謝他
The man thanks him with a quick drawing on a cocktail napkin.
你瞧 那個人 是迪士尼創辦人華特·迪士尼
For you see, that man... was Walt Disney.
而這位眼熟的小伙子 就是米老鼠
And this familiar fellow is Mickey Mouse.
不必擺出填字謎或傳家寶 二位
Yeah, no thanks on the heirloom or the crossword, guys.
一切從簡 好嗎
Let's keep it simple, okay?
親愛的 放松 你這么棒
Honey, relax. You're awesome.
肯定會很順利的
It's gonna go great.
只要我們先把這張椅子搬回到
Just as soon as we get this chair back
自我們住進來起就沒變過的位置
to where it's been ever since we've lived in this house.
媽 拜托你別再控制一切了好嗎
Mom, can you please stop managing everything?
就像她把我的帽子收藏清理掉
You mean like when she cleaned my hat collection
以防面試官檢查衣柜時看到它們
out of the front closet in case the interviewer looked in there?
親愛的 你從不戴那些帽子
Honey, you never wore those hats,
慈善機構收下時特別開心
and the charity was glad to get them.
或許你該把我的夢想也一起捐了
Maybe you should have also donated my dream
例如某天去肯塔基賽馬
of one day going to the Kentucky Derby
或去黑人教堂過復活節[都要戴帽子]
or Easter at a black church.
艾麗克斯 小貼士 面試時記得微笑
Hey, Alex. Quick tip. Smile during the interview.
我最近在心理課上
I've been learning a lot about
學了不同人格類型
different personality types in my psych course,
你算是教科書級的邊緣類型了
and you're kind of textbook borderline --
高智商 沒有共情能力
all brains, no empathy.
盧克 你這么努力學習
You know, Luke, we are so very proud
我們都很驕傲
of all the hard work you're doing,
我也很期待你學完第二章后
and I look forward to hearing your insights
會有什么樣的見解
when you finish chapter two.
不過目前而言 或許你可以先把書收起來
But for now, maybe you could just put that book away.
我就知道你會這么說
No surprise you'd say that.
控制狂 強迫癥
Controlling, obsessive --
典型的指揮官人格類型
classic Commandant personality type.
挨損了吧
Ooh, burn.
成熟點吧 海莉
Oh, grow up, Haley.
可憐的是 她做不到
Sadly, she can't.
這就是彼得·潘人格的困境
Such is the plight of the Peter Pan personality.
你是說海莉拒絕長大 我不相信
You're saying Haley refuses to grow up? I don't believe that.
接著說到另一種類型 夢想家
Which brings us to another type, the Dreamer --
白日做夢 總是很天真 很好騙
head in the clouds, tends to be naive, gullible.
你現在變聰明了我真開心
I love that you're smart now.
這就是經典的比賽日早餐
That's your classic game-day breakfast --
碳水 纖維 蛋白質
your carbs, fiber, your protein.
要是再來一口白蘭地
You throw a shot of brandy in there,
你就能參加67年的橄欖球全國錦標賽了
you'll be ready to play in the Ice Bowl.
我不吃甜菜 過去不吃 今后也不吃
I don't eat beets. Never have, never will.
你兩歲時連硬幣和蝴蝶都吃
When you were 2, you ate a dime and a butterfly.
現在你的身體倒成圣殿了
Now your body is a temple?
他可以在車上吃個蛋白質棒
He can eat a protein bar in the car.
我們還得去接住得遠的選手
We still have to pick up some players that live far away.
歌洛莉亞 這可不行
Gloria, this is not okay.
是合法的
It's legal.
他家在這個區有郵政信箱
They have P.O. Boxes in the district.
再說 每個人都鉆空子
And besides, everybody bends the rules.
我發誓另外那隊的守門員
I swear the goalie from the other team
還當過我的滴滴司機 來接過我
has been my Uber driver.
歌洛莉亞 我在想辦法讓這孩子吃蔬菜
Gloria, I'm trying to get the kid to eat his vegetables.
你得幫我一把
I could use a little support.
你怎么還沒換衣服
Why aren't you dressed?
你今天得給兩場比賽當裁判
You're supposed to referee two games today.
我告訴過你我不想當裁判
I told you I don't want to do that!
我今晚要看拳擊賽
I got my boxing match tonight.
再說 那些裁判制服傻死了
Besides, those ref outfits are stupid.
挺挺就過去了 沒事的
Walk it off. You're fine.
-快點 喬 -你沒聽出這話中的毛病了嗎
- Move it, Joe. - You're not hearing that?
海莉 跟我們說說艾麗克斯
So, Haley, you tell us about Alex.
和天才同住一間房可不容易
Well, it was not easy sharing a room with a genius.
她總是熬夜讀書 計算
She was always up reading and calculating,
但她也激勵了我
but she also inspired me.
21歲時 我對自己說
When I turned 21, I said,
"海莉 你是時候做個獨立的女人了"
"Haley, time to be your own woman,"
于是我搬進了地下室
and I moved into the basement.
抱歉 我無意打斷
I'm sorry. I don't-I don't mean to interrupt,
但我不斷回想
but I just keep replaying
我就育兒方式問題給你的回答
my answer to you about my parenting style.
不必多想
Oh, don't give it a second thought.
可當我說我想永不回頭地逃命去
But when I said I wanted to run away and never come back,
那只是個玩笑
that was a joke.
-當然 -我知道
- Yeah, absolutely. - I know.
只不過你很認真地記下來了
It's just that you wrote it down like --
-媽 別想了 -好
- Mom, let it go. - Okay.
艾麗克斯
So, Alex,
我知道你夏天是在洪都拉斯過的
I see you spent your summer in Honduras.
你還進行過哪些激勵人心的旅行
Any other travel that inspired...
鄧菲太太
Mrs. Dunphy?
假如你能在我的笑話旁
If you could maybe just make a little, like, L-O-L
小小寫上一筆"爆笑" 就很清楚了
next to my joke, so then it's super clear.
澳大利亞 我去哥斯達黎加露營過
Australia, a camping trip to Costa Rica,
-還在歐洲過了一個月 -很出眾
- and a month in Europe. - Excellent.
她的確繼承了旅行癖的血統
Well, she does come by her wanderlust honestly.
孩子們都知道我高中時的旅行
The kids here all know about my high school trip
我去了蘇聯
to the Soviet Union.
是 但是她不需要聽那些
Yeah, but she doesn't need to hear about that.
-別 請講 繼續 -在冷戰膠著時期
- No, please. Continue. - In the depths of the Cold War,
我的蹦床隊參與了文化交流活動
my tumbling team was part of a cultural exchange.
我和一個叫塞奇的蹦床家成為了朋友
I became friends with a Russian tumbler named Sergei
他想了解美國的一切
who wanted to hear all about the U.S.
他讓我回家后給他發照片
He asked me to -- to send pictures when I got home,
而且不是景點那種
and not just touristy stuff.
塞奇對日常的東西很感興趣
Sergei was interested in ordinary things --
機場啦 發電廠啦 火車站啦
uh, airports, um, power plants, train stations.
他們家是做柵欄[防御]生意的
His family was in the fence business.
他說我們的軍隊有全世界
He said our military had the best fencing...
最優秀的防護
...in the world.
我一定有給他發起碼50張
I must have sent him 50 pictures
彭德爾頓軍營的周邊圖
of the perimeter of Camp Pendleton.
總之 我們不想占用您一整天的時間
Anyway, we don't want to take up your whole day.
不然您就沒空詳細寫好報告了
You wouldn't have time to write up your report,
您可以把報告的標題寫成"艾麗克斯·鄧菲
which you could title "Alex Dunphy:
出淤泥而不染的那朵蓮花"
The Apple that fell very far from the Tree."
-非常感謝你們 我們會保持聯系的 -謝謝您
-Thank you all very much. We will be in touch. -Thank you.
-謝謝 -好 再見
-Thank you. -Okay, bye-bye.
再見 聊得很愉快
Bye. Fun chatting.
知道嗎 我們鄧菲家只要想
You know what? We Dunphys clean up
就沒有做不好的事 對吧
pretty well when we want to, don't we?
你在搞笑嗎
Are you kidding me?
媽 你就非得對她的筆記本犯強迫癥嗎
Mom, did you really have to OCD all over her notebook?
還有你 吹噓自己這么大還賴在家里住
And you, bragging about
都多大了 快30了吧
still living at home at, like, what? 30?
還有爸你 真是干得漂亮
And Dad, well done.
沒有什么比得上自己老爹是個俄羅斯間諜
There's nothing that cinches a government job
更能把握住政府工作的機會了
like finding out your dad was a Russian spy!
盧克說得太對了
Luke was right about all of you.
指揮官 彼得潘 夢想家
Commandant, Peter Pan, Dreamer.
謝謝 亞歷山德拉 在這個家里
Thank you, Alexandra. It's not easy
當個聰明人可不容易
being the smart ones in this family.
別拿你跟我比
Don't compare us!
你上一次的英語論文拿回來的時候
Your last English paper came back
貼了個"加油"加菲貓貼紙
with a Garfield sticker on it that said "Way to go!"
那是她給的第二好的貼紙了
That's the second highest sticker she gives out!
又一個新鮮雞蛋 下蛋公主的恩賜
Another fresh one, courtesy of Princess Layer.
又取一個新名字
Another new name?
她已經當過蛋格·萊恩和麻辣雞了
She's already been Egg Ryan and Chicky Minaj.
我知道擁有一只雞不是你的夢想
I know having a chicken isn't your dream.
但是如果這能讓你好受一些的話
But if it makes you feel any better,
我覺得我重新發現了自己
I think I know who I am again.
是一個討厭雞的人
A person who hates chickens!
它們又臟又蠢得要死
They are filthy and beyond stupid.
等我一找到發票
The momennt I can find the receipt,
就要退回這只雞
I am returning that chicken.
但是我不打算告訴米奇爾
But I'm not gonna let Mitchell know because,
因為就像那只麻煩鳥 我也是個惹事精
like that vile bird, I made a big stink.
我們又沒有雞食了
Oh. We're out of chicken feed again?
今天我學校有個
I have a meeting at the school today
和返校日委員會的會議
with the homecoming committee.
如果投票沒錯的話
If polling is correct,
新的皇后是坐輪椅的女孩
the new queen is gonna be in a wheelchair,
放氣球的環節超支 沒預算弄殘疾坡道了
and we already blew our ramp budget
所以能不能麻煩你去...
on a balloon drop, so could you maybe --
小卡 這是我這周第三次
Cam, this will be my third trip
去谷物飼料店了
to the feed and grain store this week.
我們說好了
We agreed that you'd be the one
由你來照顧這只討厭鬼
to take care of this awful thing.
我從未真正感覺到和動物有聯系
I've never really felt a connection to animals,
但是那只雞很特別
but there's just something about that chicken.
那深情的雙眼 緊張的小動作
The soulful eyes, the nervous movements,
頭頂上可愛的紅紅小雞冠
the cute little splash of red on top.
她真是太可愛了
She's just likeable.
另外 我超愛去那家飼料店
Plus, I love going to that feed store.
我一走進那扇門 就跟他們成了一路人
T-The second I walk through the door, I'm one of them.
-您好啊 鮑比 -你好
- Howdy, Bobby. - Hey.
聞起來像下過雨
Smells like rain.
你怎么這么快就又回來了
What are you doing back so soon?
對 我告訴過你一次應該
Yeah, I told you you got to buy
多買幾包飼料
more than one bag of feed at a time.
沒事 不麻煩
No, it's no bother.
沒事 從農田里出來透透氣挺好的
No, it's nice to get out of the field,
還能遠離雞 群
away from the chicken...s.
晚上猴啊
Evenin'.
問題是我不能讓小卡知道
The problem is I can't let Cam know
我很享受這種鄉紳生活
that I'm enjoying my new life as a gentleman farmer.
我們倆整段戀情里
I-I've spent our whole relationship
我都在試圖打壓他的鄉野氣質
trying to tamp down his farm-ness.
他就差這點鼓勵
Ugh, it's all the encouragement he'd need
就要舉家搬到密蘇里鄉下當"王老先生"[兒歌]了
to -- to move us to Missouri and go full Old MacDonald.
咿呀咿呀不要喲
E-I-E-I-no.
我沒給門上閂嗎 天啊
Did I leave that unlatched? Oh, God.
雞妮弗 雞妮弗
Hennifer? Hennifer?!
你是雷德利嗎 我是一點鐘比賽的裁判
Hey, are you Ridley? I'm reffing the 1:00 game.
我的熱狗代金券是比賽之前還是之后給
Hey, do I get my voucher for a hot dog before or after?
你的哨子呢
Oh...Hey. You got your whistle?
靠 我忘帶了
Oh, damn. I forgot it.
遲到 還沒帶哨子 你對這比賽的尊敬在哪
Late and no whistle? Where's your respect for the game?
在某個橄欖球場上吧
On a football field somewhere.
-不然你借我你的 -你開什么玩笑
- Hey, what do you say I borrow yours? - Are you kidding?
我剛因為接吻病而停了六周課
I just lost six weeks of school to mono.
你負責第四區
You're on field 4.
行了 我們快點了事吧
All right. Let's get this over with.
你是我比賽的裁判嗎
You are the referee for my game?
你對足球一點都不懂
You don't know anything about soccer.
這話留著去跟逼我到這的女人說吧
Take that up with the lady who forced me into this.
好了 紫隊 我們出發
Okay, purple, let's go!
喬 芬恩 克萊德 前鋒
Joe, Finn, Clyde up front!
盧卡斯 迪倫 查德 后衛
Lucas, Dylan, Chad in the back!
伊斯特芬 守門
Estefan, in goal!
我猜伊斯特芬是那個
I'm guessing that Estefan is the kid
住得大老遠的孩子
who lives out of the district?
他的腿毛比我都多
His legs are hairier than mine,
而且我覺得他戴了個婚戒
and I think he was wearing a wedding ring.
我們開始吧 新手
Let's get this party started, rookie.
好吧 你不吹哨他們不會開始的
Okay, they won't start unless you use the whistle.
吹哨 吹哨
Whistle! Whistle!
克萊德 空檔 進球了
Clyde, it's open! Yes!
吹哨 不算分 紫隊越位
Whistle! No goal! Purple offside!
越位 你瞎了嗎
Offside? Are you blind?
他說的對 紅隊從球現在的位置罰球
He's right. Free kick for red right where the ball is.
對 紅隊從球現在的位置罰球
Yes, free kick for red right where the ball is.
預備 吹哨
And...whistle.
幾周以來第一次 歌洛莉亞得聽我的
For the first time in weeks, Gloria had to listen to me.
我說了算 雷德利這么說的
I was in charge. Ridley said so.
得分 太棒了
Goal, yes!
教練 比分要太超前了
Coach, you're running up the score.
你得換一個弱一點的隊員
You got to sub in some of your weaker players.
那個戴著頸枕的孩子吧 這種一般都弱
How about this kid with the neck pillow? It's usually a tip-off.
我不是在超前 我是在贏
I'm not running up the score. I'm winning.
你要么換人 要么走人
You either make the substitution or you are leaving my field.
夠了 吹哨
That's it! Whistle!
你被驅逐出場了
You're out of here!
嚇不倒我
Doesn't frighten me.
這樣呢
How about that?
有點嚇人
A little bit.
你好 海莉 什么事
Oh, hey, Haley. What's up?
其實我有點生家里人的氣
I'm kind of mad at my family, actually.
他們一直說我有彼得潘人格
They keep saying I have one of those Peter Pan personalities,
所以 計劃有變
so, um, change of plans.
我們去看戲劇 不看看馬戲團了
We're going to a play, not the circus.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
迪倫 別大驚小怪
Dylan, don't make a thing out of this.
那頭大象不會記得你去年答應過
The elephant's not going to remember
今年要去看他的
you promised to see him next year.
不是 海莉我是聽不清 信號不好
No, Haley. I-I can't hear you. Bad reception.
我往前開一點
Let me move up.
艾麗克斯說對了嗎
Was Alex right?
我不知不覺中成了... 泄露機密的間諜嗎
Had I been an unwitting -- an unwitting spy?
我甚至翻出以前旅行時俄羅斯報紙
I even dug out an old article they'd done on me
刊登的關于我的舊文章
in a Russian newspaper during my trip.
塞奇告訴我文章標題是
Sergei told me the headline said,
《年輕雜技演員的友誼使命》
"Young Tumbler's Mission of Friendship."
但用谷歌翻譯掃描翻出來的
A quick scan into Google Translate
真正意思是
revealed the truth --
《知名雜技演員譴責西方》
"Famous Tumbler Denounces the West."
我需要呼吸新鮮空氣 讓腦子清醒清醒
I needed some fresh air to clear my head.
我念高中時有那么好騙嗎
Had I been that big a dupe in high school?
如果我真那么傻
And if so, what was stopping them
今天又有什么能阻止他們再次利用我
from trying to use me again today?
鄧菲先生
Hey, Mr. D!
你好啊 哥們
Hey, hey, hey! What's up, buddy?!
快把你逼瘋了 對吧 指揮官
Makes you crazy, doesn't it, Commandant?
沒有
No.
這么說你沒打算把椅子搬正
So you weren't about to straighten that chair?
因為如果世間萬物不是井然有序
Because if the whole world isn't completely ordered,
你就會感覺被萬蟻噬心
it feels like your skin is on fire?
這真是不折不扣的空談[椅子]心理學
This is literally armchair psychology.
盧克 你對我的評價很正確 我就是個夢想家
Luke, your label for me was spot on. I am a Dreamer.
不 更糟 我是容易受騙的蠢材
No, worse, I'm a -- I'm a patsy,
好傻好天真的呆瓜
a mark, a full-on sucker!
菲爾 冷靜點 你才不是好騙的笨蛋
Phil, calm down. You're not a dupe.
快坐下
Have a seat.
真可悲
Sad.
-大家好啊 -迪蘭 帽子不錯啊
- Hey, guys. - Hey, Dylan. Sweet lid.
-多少錢買的 -不要錢
- What did it cost you? - Zilch.
有人扔了很多帽子在街對面的垃圾桶里
Someone threw a bunch of them in the trash across the street.
海莉在樓下等你呢
So, uh, Haley's waiting for you downstairs.
等等 我以前也有頂類似的巴拿馬草帽...
Hang on. I used to have a Panama that looked a little like --
還有我的軟呢帽
And my fedora!
你之前騙我說要捐給"陽敏禿美組織"
You duped me into believing we were donating them to ISSBA,
其實是要把帽子都丟到垃圾堆
and you were just gonna throw them in the trash.
但這舉動傷害的不只是我 克萊爾
But this doesn't just hurt me, Claire.
還有那些"對陽光敏感的
What about the poor people at the Institute
禿頭美國人協會"的成員...
for Sun-Sensitive Bald... Americans?
對不起 我很抱歉 菲爾
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry, Phil.
只是那個女人要來采訪我們
It's just that woman was coming and the interview --
家里到處雜亂無章
and there was all that clutter.
我有病 告訴他 盧克
I'm sick. Tell him, Luke.
省省吧 克萊爾 你跟其他人都一樣
Save it, Claire. You think of me what everyone thinks of me.
覺得我是個逢被騙必中招的死蠢
I'm a rube, a pigeon, a greenhorn.
好了 迪蘭 去換身衣服 把帽子摘了
Okay, Dylan. Let's get you changed and lose the hat.
阻擋別人視線很沒禮貌
It's rude to block people's views
畢竟我們下午要去...
where we'll be spending our afternoon...
大人才會去的劇院
at an adult theater.
我們都知道
I mean, we all knew
底下還有第三頂帽子的 對吧
there was gonna be a third one, right?
-老子不知道 -好吧
- I didn't! - Okay.
-我一定是忘把門閂上了 -很有可能
- I must have left the latch open. - You probably did.
我...我知道那只雞對你有多重要
I -- I know how much that chicken means to you.
非常重要
So much.
如今發生了如此悲痛的事
And now something this painful --
我都不知道以后還有沒有勇氣再養雞了
I-I don't think I could have a chicken again ever.
等等 有監控錄像
Wait, wait. T-The security camera.
我們可以查出到底發生了什么
We can -- We can find out exactly what happened.
對 我忘了有這個
Oh, yeah. I...forgot about that.
米奇爾 米奇爾 等等 等等
Mitchell, Mitchell, wait, wait.
你不習慣面對農場生活的殘酷現實
You're not used to the harsh realities of farm life.
這些動物 看起來都很可愛
All these animals -- they seem so sweet,
但一旦表現出軟弱的一面 就會招來屠殺
but it's a bloodbath at the first sign of weakness,
就像我們跟朋友吃飯時
like dinner with our friends
有一個人起身離席后 會發生腥風血雨
when one person gets up from the table.
老天 好吧 你來看
Oh, my God. Okay, well, you -- you look
-然后告訴我發生了什么 -好
- and tell me what happened. - Okay.
等會告訴我 我離席后他們說了我什么壞話
And later, tell me what people say when I leave the table.
好了 暫時無事發生
Okay, well, nothing happening yet.
其實 我想親眼看看
Okay, you know, I want to see.
不不不 別
No. No, no, no. Don't.
不好 糟糕
Oh, no. Oh, no.
-有東西進來后院了 -是什么
- Something's come into the backyard. - What?
好像是只浣熊
I think it's a raccoon.
-蒼天啊 場面好血腥 -天啊
- OhOh th-- Oh, the horror! - Oh, my God!
不 不 她在反抗
No, no. No, she's fighting.
她在反抗 米奇爾 拼盡全力
She's fighting, Mitchell, with every fiber...
-沒錯 -憑借她不屈不撓的弱雞斗志
- That's right. - ...of her indomitable chicken-y spirit.
結束了 老天
And it's over. Oh, gosh.
阿布杜爾-賈巴爾主演的音樂劇《俄克拉荷馬》后
since a dinner theater production of "Oklahoma!"
我看過的最殘忍的農場慘劇
starring Kareem Abdul-Jabbar.
刪除
Delete. Hmm.
尸體在哪
Where's the body?
被拖走了
Um, dragged off.
那她說不定還活著
Well, then she could still be alive!
我們必須去找她
W-We have to look for her.
拿上她最喜歡的尖叫玩具
Okay. G-Grab her favorite squeak toy.
好吧 哪一個
Okay, well, which -- which one?
松鼠·鄧波兒還是獅奧納多·迪卡普里奧
Squirrely Temple or Lionardo DiCaprio?
怎么感覺你一點都不了解她
It's like you don't even know her.
"絕望的酒鬼... 破碎的生活 破碎的夢想"
"Dead-end alcoholics...broken lives, and broken dreams..."
完全沒提到蜘蛛俠
Nope, nothing about Spider-Man.
來的一定是另外一個冰人 不是蜘蛛俠的朋友
Must be a different Iceman that cometh.
沒關系 說不定也很好看
That's okay. It could still be good.
可是 迪蘭 你不能再盯著
But, Dylan, you have to stop looking
那邊的嘉年華了
at the carnival over there.
抱歉 但如果我知道之后
I'm sorry, but it just might be easier to enjoy
我們會"行"去那邊 "耍"碰碰車
this unsparing look at life's castoffs
我會更容易欣賞
if I knew that afterwards,
這出描繪人生失敗者的
we were gonna walketh over there
殘忍戲劇
and goeth to the bumper cars.
我只是要你花...
I'm literally asking for only...
四個半小時
4 1/2 hours?
我知道你想證明我們是成熟的大人
Look. I know you want to prove that we're mature adults,
但你看看排隊的人
but look at this line.
我們在這里就是年輕人
We are the young people here.
然而
Whereas...
在嘉年華那邊 我們就會是
At the carnival, we'd be, like,
年紀最大的人
the oldest people there?
我能提醒你 上次他們押送我們
May I remind you what they said to us last time
離開球池時 說了什么嗎
when they escorted us out of the ball pit?
"不好意思 這個娛樂設施不是給..."
"Excuse me, but this attraction really isn't for..."
"成年人玩的"
"adults."
-我的夫人 -我的迪蘭
- M'lady. - M'Dylan.
好了 我們需要談談
Okay, we need to talk.
我們當然得好好談一下
You bet we need to talk.
我把你趕出比賽 是我過分了
I was out of bounds throwing you out of that game.
你把我趕出比賽 當然過分了
You bet you were out of bounds throwing me out of that game.
但一切都是我的錯 杰
But it was all my fault, Jay.
一切當然都是我的錯 杰
You bet it was all my fault, Jay --
別用兔八哥那招陷害我重復你說的話
Don't Bugs Bunny me.
好吧 我們都喜歡當掌控全局的人
Okay. So we both like to be in charge.
但關系到喬時 我們能不能立場一致
But when it comes to Joe, can we both be on the same page?
比如今早我試著勸他
Like this morning when I was trying to get him
吃蔬菜時 支持我一下
to eat his vegetables? Back me up.
我就知道我該扔了那些甜菜根
I knew I should have thrown away those beets!
太蠢了 我是4歲小屁孩嗎
Stupid. What am I, 4?
我們好像是沒能樹立起正確的榜樣
I guess we're not setting a very good example.
沒錯 我們對對方說不
Exactly! When we say no to each other,
他就認為他可以對我們說不
he thinks he can say no to us.
對 比如他的功課 上床睡覺時間
Yeah, like for his homework, his bedtime --
或者重要的事 例如吃有營養的食物
Or something important like eating those nutritious...
-吹哨 -吹哨
- Whistle! - Whistle!
菲爾
Phil, look.
帽子的事我騙了你 很抱歉
I'm really sorry I lied to you about the hats.
但憑良心說 你的確是會...
But in all fairness, you do have a tendency to --
又來了 又要說我舍不得丟東西嗎
This again? How I can't throw anything away?
我們家有錄了100集的《囤積狂》節目
We have 100 episodes of "Hoarders" on DVR
你想看隨時都能看
in case you want to watch them again.
我的重點不在這里
That's not what this is about.
是無論誰跟我說什么
This is about me blindly believing
我都會盲目相信
whatever anybody tells me.
你這樣太苛責自己了
You're being too hard on yourself.
你總想看到人最好的一面
You want to see the best in people.
并不代表你就真的什么鬼話都會信啊
It doesn't mean you're gonna believe just anything.
真的嗎 那你說說我們珍愛的傳家寶
Really? What about our beloved family heirloom?
-克萊爾 -怎么
- Claire? - Hmm?
這是真貨嗎 還是我只是第四代的鄧菲傻子
Is this real, or am I just a fourth-generation Dunphy dummy?
米奇的肩膀的確有些過壯
Well, uh, Mickey's shoulders are a bit muscular.
但或許是迪士尼的創辦人
But, perhaps, Walt customized it
為你的曾祖父所特別設計的版本嘛
for your great-grandfather because he was, uh --
他是個港口工人是嗎
He was a longshoreman?
他是女士帽子的商販
He sold ladies' bonnets. Oh.
媽 你能把爸的信用卡
Mom, can you slip Dad's credit card
在他發現之前塞回他...
back in his wallet before he --
你好啊 帥哥
Oh. Hey, handsome.
再次證明你們就是...
Further proof of how you all see me --
把我當成腦子被門夾過的傻子
as a turnip truck faller-offer!
-才沒有 -那我問你
- No. - Then I'll ask you.
你相信這是華特·迪士尼先生畫的嗎
Do you believe that this was drawn by Walt Disney?
艾麗克斯 你進來
Alex, get in here.
-艾麗克斯 -別啊 親愛的 你知道她會說什么
- Alex! - No, honey, you know what she's gonna say.
她的驗光師都不準她戴隱形眼鏡
Her optometrist won't even let her wear contacts
因為她翻白眼過于頻繁... 你來啦
'cause of all the excessive eye rolling. - Hi.
我想知道真相
I need to know the truth.
艾麗克斯 真貨還是假貨
Alex, real or unreal?
真貨
Real.
的確 是有些不像 但你不是說過
Yeah, it's a little off, but didn't you say
他當時得在卡車貨斗里畫嗎
he had to draw it in the back of a truck?
而且什么人搭便車會隨身攜帶繪圖鉛筆啊
And what hitchhiker would be carrying around a drafting pencil
肯定是卡通繪畫師之類的嘛
if he wasn't some sort of an animator?
而且誰會沒油了淪落到道路一旁呢
And who would run out of gas on the side of the road
肯定是個滿眼光芒并幻想著
but a starry-eyed dreamer envisioning
世界上最快樂之處的夢想家吧
the happiest place on earth?
所以 是真貨
So...real.
另外 我得到那份工作了
Also I got the job.
-什么 -很棒啊
- What? - Hey.
是啊 他們剛打電話通知 我還在感到震驚呢
Yeah, they just called. I'm still in shock myself.
親愛的 我好為你驕傲
Oh, honey. I'm so proud of you.
讓我去開一瓶香檳慶祝
Oh, let me get some champagne.
盧克 來幫我拿杯子
Luke, help me with the glasses.
艾麗克斯 太棒了 我就知道你能行
Alex, that's amazing. I knew you could do it.
你對所有事情都這么樂觀
You say that about everything.
-是啦 但是... -不 我是想謝謝你
- Well, I know, but... - No, thank you.
學騎自行車 我的首次大提琴發表會
Riding a bike, my first cello concert,
大一化學課 這份工作
freshman chemistry, this job --
每次我確信自己做不到某件事的時候
every time I was sure I couldn't do something,
你都能讓我對自己有信心
you convinced me I could.
家里有一個愿意相信的人真好
It's nice to have a believer in the house.
到處都找不到她
I don't see her anywhere.
轉個彎去那一邊找找吧
All right, let's maybe turn around and look over there?
米奇爾 為什么雞要過馬路
Okay, Mitchell, why would the chicken cross the road?
我其實完全沒帶他在找雞
We were never finding that chicken.
在經過一陣不愉快的搏斗之后
After an unpleasant struggle that I only won
我在身中無數爪的情況下活了下來
after sustaining multiple scratches,
并把雞放到了我們車的后座上
I put it in the back seat of my car,
開車送到了一個產蛋場 把它丟進了圍欄
drove it to the egg farm, and lobbed it over the fence.
雞稍微能飛啦
They can fly a little.
你的手臂上都是抓傷 怎么了
Oh, your arm's all scratched up. What happened?
大概是我出手阻止
Oh, um, it's probably from when I was trying to
兩只冠藍鴉的打架時留下來的吧
break that fight up with those, um -- those blue jays.
哎喲 媽呀
Oh. Oh, gosh. Oh, God.
我的老天啊
Oh, man.
我突然感覺好困啊
I am all of a sudden feeling very tired.
-需要換我來開車嗎 -不用 沒事的
- Well, do you want me to drive? - No, no, it's fine.
-小卡 小心 -天啊
- Cam, watch out! - Oh, my God!
你把雞妮弗給丟了對吧
You got rid of Hennifer.
對啦 我承認
Okay, I admit it.
我討厭那只雞 我又沒臉
I hated that chicken, and I was too ashamed
說出這件事 因為我為了你把我的
to say anything because I -- I made such a big stink
鄉下魂給吐槽沒了的事 跟你抱怨那么久
out of you shaming the country out of me.
我也要道歉
I'm sorry.
我想坦白一件事
I have a confession.
-我愛那只雞 -真的嗎
- I love that chicken. - Really?
我不想承認這件事 因為我想保持我自己
I-I didn't want to admit it because I like to see myself
是那種... 你懂的 精致高雅的都市人
as a sort of, you know, sophisticated urbanite.
但我想你...
But I guess you --
你稍微把我鄉下化了一點
you countrified me a little.
你也都市化了我
Well, you citified me.
-好像有點甜呢 -是啊
- Aww, that's kind of sweet. - It is.
我們現在只需要去找到一件活動
You know, now we just need to find an activity
能滿足你心中那個叼稻草鄉村男孩
that satisfies the straw-chewing country boy in you
與我心中那個喜愛櫥窗購物的都市男孩
and the window-shopping cosmopolitan in me.
順著這條路往下開
Drive up the road a piece.
問你啊 這馬用洗發水貓能用嗎
Now, will this horse shampoo harm a cat?
因為我... 我好喜歡這香味
Because I just -- I love the scent.
領子翻還是不翻
Collar up or down?
翻下來
Uh, down.
我會讓你嘗到報應的
You'll pay for that!
天啊 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
暫停 暫停 我看到了自己的倒影
Timeout, timeout! I just saw my reflection!
我就說那個西班牙糖棒會把我口紅弄沒
I told you that churro was going to drink up my lipstick.
暫停結束
Time in!
天啊
Oh, my God!
迪蘭 口紅斷進我鼻孔了
Dylan, the lipstick went up my nose!
斷在里面深處啊
It's really jammed up there!
好的 你別動 海莉
Oh, okay. Stay still, Haley.
我... 我去從另一邊撞你
I'll -- I'll hit you from the other side.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
通知你們一下 X光顯示鼻梁沒斷
Just want to let you know, the x-ray shows no broken nose.
我猜你看出來我們有點幼稚了
I guess you figured out we were acting kind of childish.
還能玩的時候就要玩到最瘋嘛
Enjoy it while you can, right?
對啊 誰說我們要拼命長大成人啊
Yeah. Who says we have to race into being adults?
誰會不想享受無憂無慮的生活
Why wouldn't you want to enjoy a carefree life
而且要越久越好呢
as long as you could?
至少到生孩子前都能這樣啊
At least until the baby comes.
那還有好多年呢 相信我
Oh, that's years away. Trust me.
其實我們在麻醉前都會先驗血
Actually, we always run a blood test before anesthesia.
你懷孕了
You're pregnant.
我們可以在這里耗一整晚
We can be here all night.
我不能啊
I couldn't.
我要去小短家看拳賽 都遲到了
I was late to watch the fight at Shorty's.
等我到的時候
By the time I got there,
波蘭香腸好的部分肯定都被他們吃光了
the Polish sausage was gonna be down to those puckered end pieces.
聽我說 我妥協了
Listen, I'll meet you halfway.
當你媽沒在看的時候
When your mother's not looking,
你吃甜菜根 我就吃甜菜根
you eat a beet, I eat a beet.
同意嗎
Deal?
親愛的 我能喝點酒嗎
Mi amor, can I get some wine?
伊斯特芬的父親打電話來了
That was Estefan's father.
綠哥布林隊想挖角他
The Green Goblins are trying to recruit him.
我需要去一趟提款機
I need to stop by the ATM
然后去他家坐坐
and then go to his house.
你爸爸不注意的時候
When your daddy's not looking,
我們就一人吃一塊甜菜根好嗎
let's split the beets, okay?
好吧 我決定要吃了
Fine. I'm ready to eat these,
但我們能不能關燈
but can we turn off the lights
我吃的時候不想看它們惡心的樣子
so I don't have to see how gross they are?
-有道理 -好主意
- Makes sense. - Good idea.
-太棒了 寶貝 -我的乖兒子啊
- Bravo, papi! - That's my guy!